Then the next part, basically,
下面介绍下个任务
what we want to do is we want to say if a user doesn't have
如果某个用户
an array attached to it of more than two movies,
没有关联超过 2 部电影的数组
then we actually don't want to keep them into
那么我们不会将他们保留在数据集中
our dataset to figure out who they're related to.
因为不需要判断他们与谁相关
We should use a different method than
我们应该使用其他方法
maybe some collaborative filtering method
而不是协同过滤方法
to make recommendations for those individuals.
向这些用户推荐电影
So in order to do that,
为了删除这些用户
I'll set up another dictionary which will just hold the values of
我将设置另一个字典
this movie-seen- dictionary that have an array of more than two.
该字典会存储 movies_seen 字典中电影超过 2 部的数组值
So I'm going to set that up as just movies_to_analyze,
字典名称设为 movies_to_analyze
which is the thing will return at the end of this,
在此单元格结束时将返回该字典
and what we'll do is,
下面创建 for 循环
for the user_id movies, and the movies_seen.items.
for user_id, movies in movies_seen.items()
So this used to be added items and Python2,
之前是在 Python2 里添加项目
but now, it's just items in Python3.
现在是在 Python3 中添加项目
If the length of the movie is greater than that lower bound,
如果 movies 的长度大于下限
then what we want to do is we want to take movies_to _analyze.
那么会将它附加到 movies_to _analyze 上
I'm going to take the key, which is the user_Id and attach to it movies,
我将传入键 即 user_id 并附加该 movies
otherwise, we just want to get rid of it.
否则删除它
So I think that should do it,
这样就可以了
it will take too long.
运行时间很长
In this next part, what we want do is look at
在下一部分
the relationships between those individuals.
我们将查看这些用户之间的关系
What that means is we want to look the movies that user1 has seen,
也就是说 我们将查看 user1 看过的电影
look at the movies user2 has seen.
并查看 user2 看过的电影
When they've seen the same lines,
当他们看过相同的电影时
we want to assess how related those two individuals are to one another.
我们将评估他们之间的关系如何
So the way we could do that is we could pull the movies that user1 has seen.
我们将提取 user1 看过的电影
Basically, from that dictionary,
我们将从刚刚创建的字典中进行提取
we just created, we're passing in this user1,
传入这个 user1
and we're going to pull their movies and store them in movies1,
提取出他看过的电影并存储到 movies1 中
and we can do the same thing with movies2.
movies2 也一样
So we have these two sets of movies.
我们获得了两个电影集合
Then if we want to know which movies they've both seen,
为了查看他们都看过的电影
we can use this intersect1d,
我们可以使用 intersect1d()
which you actually saw in Juno's lessons.
如果你学习过数据科学课程
If you are going through the data science program,
就会在 Juno 的课程中见过 intersect1d()
but this is a really fast way to pull the intersection of these two arrays.
通过它可以快速获取这两个数组之间的交集
Then to speed it up even more,
还可以进一步提高速度
you can say assume you need equals true,
在这里输入 =true
which is fair in our case.
这对于我们的示例来说没问题
But if that's not true,
如果不为 true
then this isn't something that you should add,
那么不应该添加进来
but it can make your operations even that much faster.
=true 使代码运行速度更快
From there, what I want to do is I'm going to create
接下来
this DataFrame where I'm going to pull
我将创建这个 DataFrame
the rows for each one of these users and the location of their similar movies,
并提取每个用户所在的行和相似电影的位置
and I'm going to pull all of those ratings.
我将提取所有这些评分
So I want to hold two arrays or in this case, a DataFrame.
我将存储两个数组 即这个 DataFrame
That's basically, each row is a user and the columns will be there matching movies,
每行代表一个用户 每列代表匹配的电影
and then what's filled into there is
填充的是一个密集矩阵
just an actually dense matrix where we have their ratings for all of those things.
其中包含每部电影的评分
So this will be a DataFrame,
这将是一个 DataFrame
where we're pulling from that original matrix that user_by_movie,
我们将从原始矩阵 user_by_movie 中提取数据
if you remember, this was a really sparse matrix from before.
这是一个很稀疏的矩阵
But we want to pull where user1 is and where user2 is as the rows.
我们要提取出 user1 和 user2 所在的行
We want to pull their similar movies, this intersection part here.
我们要提取他们的相似电影 即这个交集部分
So we're going to pull the location of those parts and then I actually found
我们将提取这些部分的位置
this on Stack Overflow post is how do I compute
我在 Stack Overflow 帖子中找到了
the correlation between these things?
这个计算相关性的方法
You could use something like your function from the earlier part,
你可以使用之前的函数
but it's probably faster to do this with some sort of NumPy operation.
但是使用 NumPy 运算方法速度更快
So if we do transpose corr, sorry, it gives you a grid.
我们将使用 transpose().corr() 它会返回一个网格
So you can actually run df.transpose.corr.
你可以对任何 DataFrame
You can run this on any DataFrame,
运行这个 df.transpose().corr()
and it'll give you the correlation between all the columns.
它将返回所有列之间的关系
So this transpose is taking
transpose() 会接受用户
the users and moving them out of the rows and in to the columns,
将他们从行中移到列中
computing the correlation between those two users,
corr() 会计算两个用户之间的关系
and then you end up with a matrix where the diagonal is
结果是一个矩阵
all ones because that's the correlation of each column with itself,
对角线上的值都为 1 因为它们表示每列与本身的关系
and then on the off-diagonals as each pairwise correlation.
非对角线上的值表示成对的关系
So with that, we can compute the correlation between any two individuals.
现在我们可以计算任何两个用户之间的关系了
So this is between any two individuals and you can
这是任何两个用户之间的关系
imagine doing this for all possible pairs of users.
我们可以对所有可能的用户对完成这一计算流程
So go through every pair of users,
对所有的用户对运行此 compute_correlation() 函数
run this compute correlation to get the correlation coefficient between them.
获取它们之间的相关系数
That's essentially what I did with this pickle.
这就是这个 pickle 的作用
So what holds is the columns of the two years those that were passed,
它存储的是传入的两个用户对应的列以及他们的关系
as well as their correlation for every pair of users.
这里针对的是所有的用户对